Pooja lives in one of the rural areas of India
where access to banking services is
not easy. She has to travel long distances to
her nearest village bank even to check her account balance.
We understand the problems faced by many people like Pooja,
especially those
living in rural areas, and hence, the
student organization of all their videos. NPCI is introducing Aadhaar Enabled Payment
System (PDS). This is
a model operated by NPCI Bank that
allows online financial inclusion transactions at micro ATMs through any bank business correspondent using Aadhaar credentials. This
includes
KYC (Key Entity Validation) of financial transactions. The
use of biometric information in the UIDAI database for customer authentication makes it easy to conduct banking transactions
in remote areas of India without any hassle. To complete a
transaction, Anupriya only needs to go to a
business correspondent,
enter her Aadhaar number, inform the business correspondent of the
transaction type, name of the bank, and the
amount, and
give her biometric fingerprint or fingerprint at the micro ATM. After the transaction is completed, the
banking correspondent, such as Bank
Mitra, gives Pooja a copy of the transaction.  This gives a rope
which can be used in future.
Now Pooja can do the usual transactions like balance
enquiry, cash withdrawal, cash deposit, mobile number
update, mini statement in Aadhaar database, Aadhaar to Aadhaar fund
transfer within minutes.
Pooja can now also send amount by entering the beneficiary's Aadhaar number,
amount, name of the beneficiary, bank's Aadhaar number.
Customers
can open new bank accounts instantly through PKYC or electronic KYC
which is beneficial for both the bank and the customer. Simply get
your bank to do KYC to open your bank account easily.
Now Pooja will get KYC 100% secure and easy.
Use Pink Print Depiction technology. GPS transactions are always seamless.
You can avail this new age banking service which enables the
bank to carry out
Aadhaar enabled* banking transactions through the Central Secretariat and Clearing Agency.
Operated by NPCI with member banks, we are dedicated to making it
available even in the remotest parts of the country
and connecting every region and society of the country to the mainstream banking.
Use GPS system for safe and fast transactions. Reach your nearest
Business Correspondent and
start your day with a simple Aadhaar Enabled Payment
System